Wrege, Charles D. Research Papers 6395
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series XI: Rutgers University, the Academy of Management, and the History of Management
  - Rutgers - University College and Management Dept. MEMOS, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Conflict Between F. W. Taylor and F. B. Gilbreth at New England Butt Co., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Data on Proposed Book on Management by Department of Management Rutgers, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    rejected by C. Wrege Editor
  - Wrege - notes on March 8, 1967 meeting at Rutgers "Matching Jobs and Engineers" (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - N. P. Alifas, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Data on Honors Program at Rutgers, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - C. D. Wrege "Introduction to Management 401" Rutgers, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Data on Job Demand, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Paul Peters, "Errors in Historical Documents" (on Nikola Tessla), 1970 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with Fred Kaempf, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Cara L. Herman Paper, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Symectics & C. D. Wrege in Beat (Rutgers), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Archives and Manuscript Collections for Students of Management History, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - John Stelling Thompson & Lichter Co., 1977 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Feiss Data for Golden Book, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - letters at Rutgers for "Lindbach Award" etc., 1978 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Nite Beat Newspaper of Rutgers University College on "Wrege's Raiders", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Research Reports Outline, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - U. S. Patent Office - Trademark Section, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Data on Holland Submarine VI 1896-1898, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Application for a University Grant, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Some Observations on the Present Offerings of the Department of Management, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Department of Management, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Letter on Appointment to Editorial Board of the Association of Human Resources Management and Organizational Behaviors, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - C. D. Wrege "Report on Research Accomplishments", 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Bicentennial data (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Report to Dean Kraft - Rutgers University, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - C. D. Wrege - Suggested Steps in Research Rutgers, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Edward Filene Data & 20th Century Fund, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Kathy Drury, 70 C Farm Road, Somerville, NJ, 08876, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - National City Lines, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Transition Program - Rutgers, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Timothy Stearns Correspondence, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    on C. D. Wrege selection in management
  - "Scientific Management" for Encyclopedia of Science, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - NJ Engineer Study Wrege Rutgers (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Ode to Professor Wrege (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Richard Fiess Data, 1942-1959 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - How to Find an Individual (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Dynamics of Behavior C. D. Wrege - Bureau of Government Research (Box 9, Folder 63)
    Rutgers Wrege Personal
  - Richard A. Feiss, 1958-1963 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence on Establishing a History of Management Course at NYU Fall 1959 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    John Mee letters
  - Data on "Gates VII Arrow" System B. B. Small, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    Engineering Research Center
  - Union-Management Cooperation at the Naumkeag Steam Cotton Mills" 1928, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Study of Webster Lens Co., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    antique manufacturer of ground lenses for optical glasses; Webster, MA
  - Morris D. Barrie "A Study of Napoleon's Logistics for the Russian Campaign of 1812: Factor Myth?", 1971 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    Rutgers
  - Scientific Management, Systematic Management and Labor 1880-1915, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - History in Boxes paper, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Industrial Management Manuscript, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    Chapters 1-4
  - The "Search for Schmidt," a Case Study Illustrating Research Methods Available to Management Historians, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Dr. A. F. Pawley Telephone - 1863 Asbury Park Journal, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Finding the "Stuff" of Management History, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - "The Human Side of Enterprise's Forty-Five Years Before McGregor, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - The Management Historian as Detective, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - The Truth About "Schmidt", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Copies of Original Manuscripts Released to the History of Management Thought, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence with William Gay & Art Bedian on Southard, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Henry Lawrence Gantt R. W. Rey, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Management Consulting 1913-1926 The Keppelle Hall Papers, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - The Men Before Mayo, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - "Secret Alliance Sept" paper, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Babson College - Archives, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - The Efficient Management of Hospitals Proceedings, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - List of Individuals and Organizations Concerned with Hospital Efficiency 1910-1920, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    2 pages
  - Management and the Home Articles, etc., 1980 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    (See Ladies Home Journal 1911)
  - 1980 The Past Helps the Present (Box 9, Folder 89)
    Midwest Academy of Management
  - A pioneer for his hospitals: The End Result System at Codman Hospital, 1911-1918 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Discovering the Roots of Scientific Management, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Mary Franzure Marketing Project, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    Home Management 1913, Christine Frederick
  - Nancy Hendridison on Manufacturing Investment Company, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Bancroft & Sons 1982 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Edison Accounting - Papers Project, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Double Jeopardy: To Be a Management Pioneer and a Woman, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Mary B. Gilson: A Historical Study of the Neglected Accomplishments of a Woman Who Pioneered in Personnel Management, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Improving Health Care through Scientific Management, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    American Institute of Decision Sciences
  - Academy Pattison, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Midwest Case Writers Association, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    Business History Conference
  - Data on Charles Babbage, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Data on Mary Follett, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Inquiry data (including paper from Bishop Brent files in library of Congress), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Manuscript for Review of Business & Economic Research on "Medical Men and Scientific Management", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Proof of Scientific Management & Medical Management Paper, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Robert Pethia "Pseudo Management History", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Gantt Data from Pete Peterson, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - John Herder "Creative Social Research", 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    American Unitarian Association
  - Origins of Small Grown Research: Some New Perspectives, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Unknown Pioneer Work of the "Inquiry" on the Study of Group Relationships 1921-1930, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Richard Feiss "Mutual at Western Reserve University, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Social Strikes, Scientific Management & The Hawthorne Studies 1914 - 1933 Distinguished Paper, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - an unusual management information study of the 1920s, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Paper on I.M.I., 1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Salinger films on C. D. Wrege's role in film on the History of Management, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - C. Wrege "System Analysis Before 1924", 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "The Duty of Every Generation", 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Mrs. Richard A. Feiss 1959 and Kappele Hall letter 1926, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Management Research Association, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Brian Price 1987 - on Scientific Management Proposal for American Historians Conference (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Robert Hoxie Data, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Dr. Dau Jon Bal paper, Academy of Management, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Two Pioneers in Organizational Behavior Before 1920, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Manuscript
  - New Insight Into the Contributions of the First Industrial Counseler, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Valentine Paper, Wrege & Thomas Taylor (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Pioneer Work in Diagramming and Controlling Information Flow in Large Organizations: 1899-1923" paper for 1993 Academy Meeting, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Searching Deeds from 1930 to Present, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Memorandum from Jane Gibson "Management History & Today's Gurus", 1996 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Little Things Mean a Lot, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Management History
  - Thomas Miller - University of Memphis, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - The Flying Horse: Eadward Muybridge's Contribution to Motion Study, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - What we don't know about management history, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Alive or Dead, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Searching for the Unknown: Hunting for Historic Manuscripts, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Searching for the Insignificant, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Synetics: Creative Problem Solving, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Where Scientific Management Went Awry, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    Morgan Witzel
  - Advice to Management Historians, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - The Emporer's New Clothes: Searching for the Hawthorne Film, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Management Myth: Atlantic Monthly, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Work Related Travel and Job Autonomy, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Macro vs. Micro Approach in Management History (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Raymond Avon, "Evidence & Inference in History" Daedelus (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Central Station Management, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Control and Competitiveness in Pennsylvania Anthracite: The Subcontracting and Leasing System (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Charlie Day Charts (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Dolphin Jute Mills, Paterson, NJ (Box 10, Folder 41)
    site of Industrial Lighting test 1918
  - Marie Hennen Feiss Material (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - 1921- "Formula for an Efficient Workman" (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Bancroft Gheradi, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - "Health Management in Industry" J. D. Hickett, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - A Historian Looks at Organizational Research Paper (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Human Engineering Aspects of Farm Equipment (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Human Relations (Box 10, Folder 48)
    D. C. Lodge
  - Illumination-Production-Investigation at John Sidzrotham Tape Mills (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - International Management Institute: Work Done for the League of Nations, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Learning to Learn, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Methods of Research (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Mitshorlich Patents for Sulphite Paper & G. N. Fletcher (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Management in Historical Perspective (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Output & Weather Transparencies, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    Prof. Elsworth Huntington
  - The Practicability of Ratings in Appointments and Promotion of Members of the Visiting Staff, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Random Notes on the Concept that Piggybacking is Progressive Railroad Management in Action (Box 10, Folder 57)
    Raymond A. Sipler
  - Recollections of Ernest E. Southard, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    Robert M. Yirkes
  - Restriction of Output, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Scientific Management in New York Times, 1910-1911 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Sanford Thompson "Postwar Marketing", 1948 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Before Bales, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Academy of Management Review, Review of "Parallelism of Knowledge & the Inevitability of Scientific Management", 1994 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Review of "How Historians See", 1995 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Academy of Management Review - Methods Paper 1995 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Review of AMR 94 "Exploring the Past", 1995 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Letters, Reviews, etc. On Academy of Management Review, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Academy of Management Review, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Journal of Management Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - For Journal of Management History files, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    early version of "Management & the Worker: A Dubious Document"
  - Journal of Management History, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    Jack Rubin (Editor)
  - Illustration for Journal of Management History paper "When Little Things Mean A Lot", 1995 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Journal of Management History, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - New Method to Research Management History: What We Don't Know About Management History, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Journal of Management History, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - David Lamond - Journal of Management History (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Journal of Management History Reviews (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Michael Rowlinson, Management & Organizational History (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - N-File for Spring, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - N-File, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Taylor & Thompson material for N-File, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - N-File Newsletter Editor, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - N-File 1980 - On Academy Archives (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - N-File Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Academy Data, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Jamison letter on Academy Files, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence on 1979 paper on "Decision Modela", 1978 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    Eastern Academy of Management
  - Wills Working Paper, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    Academy of Management
  - Academy of Management Origins of Centennial idea, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Achieving Social Change Through Scientific Management, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    Manuscript, Academy of Management
  - C. D. Wrege, "Clues to Management History: Some Unusual Sources", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - C. Wrege "Elton Mayo's Many 'Hands'", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    Academy Proceedings
  - Convention Correspondence, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Manuscript of Paper on Munsterberg Decision Studies, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    Academy
  - Convention Correspondence, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - 43rd Convention Program, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Convention Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - "Before Bales" Academy of Management, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Pete Peterson & Proposed Symposium on "The Path to Bethlehem", 1984 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - The Historian Looks at Unusual Management Information Systems of the 1920s, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Convention Correspondence, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Frederich W. Taylor in the 1880s Abstract, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Notes on Meeting of Management History Division of the Academy in 1985 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Convention Correspondence, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Prospectors for the Proceedings of the Management Centennial Academy of Management, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Management Centennial, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Inception, Early Struggles and Flowering of the Academy of Management CD Wrege, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Convention Correspondence, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - International Management Institute, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Management History Division Program (Box 11, Folder 5)
    letters
  - Papers Reviewed for 1990 Academy Meeting (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Call for Papers, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Research Methods Division Executive Elections Ballot, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Academy Paper, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Reflections on the Hawthorne Studies (Box 11, Folder 10)
    75 Years Later
  - Evaluations of Papers for Academy of Management History Division, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Academy of Management Cornell Memorandum of Agreement, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Academy of Management Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Academy of Management Data, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Stransby letter to L. L. Cummings of Academy (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Letter to Richard Whiting on Academy, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - History of Applied Organization, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Study at Harvard
  - Private Schools & University Historical Records Project, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Memo to William Raimond, Rutgers University - on New School of Business, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - General Letters, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - George Gore Letter on C. D. Wrege's History of the Academy, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Academy Archives data, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Past, Present, Future of Academy of Management Archives, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - George Gore Letters, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Frank Hoy Letters regarding David Mittori's Paper on Taylor and Carnegie, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Academy Stationery (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence on International Management Institute firm 20th Century (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Taylor Society Survey, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Taylor Society Thompson Papers, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Society for the Advancement of Management (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - H. K. Hathaway on "Standards" Taylor Society Bulletin, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Taylor Society Dinner, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Percy C. Brown Correspondence with George S. Gibb of Harvard on Proposed "History of Taylor Society", 1952 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - John Carmody papers and Correspondence with Francis M. Seeber, Supervising Archivist, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - William Latham, Taylor Society Records, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Search for Taylor Society Records (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Dodge data (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Keppele Hall Data (Box 11, Folder 38)
- Series XII: Streetcars and Railroads
  - Grand Rapids Railways Newsclippings, 1925-1929 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Charles A. Coffin Foundation Award, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Grand Rapids Ry. Fame in "A Citizens History of Grand Rapids", 1926 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Robert Sutton, Letter on Experimental Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Norman Krentel (Box 11, Folder 43)
    Geneva, IL
  - Photograph of Grand Rapids Railway Trolley, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Kathy Barks: Grand Rapids, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Grand Rapids Railway Paper (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Data on Street Railways (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Public Service Railway of New Jersey, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Family Tree of Public Services Electric and Gas Company (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Historic Roster of Public Service Railways (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Russel Shapley letters, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Bergen County Street Railways (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - PSCRY Lodi Line Maps (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - PSCRY Southern Division Maps (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - PSCRY Arcola Substation (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - PSCRY Terminal (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - PSCRY Newark, NJ Streetcars (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Public Service Car Statistics (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Public Service Corporation Railway Correspondence, 1981-1993 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Public Service Coordinated Transport's "Newark Experiment" Street Cars 1934-1936 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Managerial Practices of Electric Railway Companies in New Jersey: 1890-1920, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Myers - Dean Automobile's Accident, 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Jitney Data (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Public Service Buses, 1924-1928 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Mack Trucks and Motor Coaches (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Streetcars and Trainers, 1903-1923 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Birney Streetcars, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    1915-1928
  - Fighting the Jitneys: The Origins of Public Service Co-ordinated Transport 1907-1928, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Experimental Streetcars, 1927-1936 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Bay City Traction and Electric Company, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Buffalo, New York, Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Chicago, Illinois, Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Cincinnati, Ohio, Street Car (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Consolidated Traction Data and Taylor, Whitney (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Kansas City, Missouri, Streetcars (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Muskogee, Oklahoma (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - New York City, New York, Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Philadelphia, PA Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Queens and Long Island Trolleys (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - St. Louis Car Co. (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Salt Lake City, Utah, Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Tampa, Florida, Street Cars (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Early British Patents on Electric Railways, 1840-1855 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Ed Blake & Management 314 (Traffic Management) (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Street Railway Financiers (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Psychological Tests for Accidents (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - PCC, Operations Research and Management Research Groups (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Charles O. Birney, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    Seattle, Washington
  - Street Car Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Paper on Experimental Cars, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Reductions of Figures for Marketing Paper (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Street Railway Trailers References (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - "Bustrailer" Photograph, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Manuscript for Drew Paper, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - The Trolley Runs Again on the War, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Albert Mankoff Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Albert Mankner Novels (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Correspondence Regarding McCallum and the Erie Plan (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Daniel McCallum Data (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Articles on D. C. McCallum, 1942-1950 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - McCallum's Inflexible Arched Truss Bridge, 1859 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - The Watermill, and Other Poems (Box 11, Folder 102)
    D. C. McCallum (photocopy)
  - McCallum in Ohio (Box 11, Folder 103)
    Erie
  - McCallum Bridge Company (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Masons, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Thompson Skinner Brown Data (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - William J. Wilgus Data (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report of the New York and Erie Railroad Company (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - By-Laws and Regulations of the New York and Erie Railroad Company, 1841 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report of the Directors of the New York and Erie Railraod Company, 1853 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    pages 13-16
  - Reports of the President and Superintendent of the New York and Erie Railroad Company, 1855 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Pages 160-180
  - Handbook of Railroad Construction, 1857 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    page 413
  - New York & Northern Rail Road Annual Report, 1892 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Reports of the New York Railroad Commissioners, 1889 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Erie Railroad Data (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Telegraph Codes (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Search for Erie Chart (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Data on Railroad Serials (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Erie R. R. Organization Chart in American Railroad Journal (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Eleazer Lord's "Castle" (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Piermont, New York
  - Western New York Railway Historical Society (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Working for the Railroad, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Denise C. McCallum's Life After Erie (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Erie Paper Exhibits 15-17 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Daniel Craig McCallum: From Bridges to the Erie Plan (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Discovered After 150 Years: The Visionary 1855 Organization Plan of the New York and Erie Railroad (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Closing Chandler's Gap, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - American Railroad Journal, 1849-1855 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Chandler's Footnotes
  - Management in the American Railroad Journal (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Series XIII: Personal
  - Correspondence: General (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: General, 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: General, 1980-1989 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: General, 1990-1999 (Box 12, Folder 29)